hey everyone welcome back to another
lesson in this tosa automation
playlist today I'm going to tell you how
you can do multilingual testing using
tosa now what does it mean so if your
application or your website has got
multiple languages so this particular
website uh is from Nikon and it is a
Canadian website but but it has got two
languages as you can see this is the
English language and then there is also
an option for French right so if I click
on the French link then uh it converts
everything on this page to the French
language now this is a very common
scenario which you come across web
applications when uh there are multiple
languages supported by that web
application then uh you need to test um
with every language now how you can do
this easily with tosa so let's get
started I'm going back to English now
what I have done in tosa is I have
already added a module for this page and
what uh we want to do is just want to
click on this camera's link okay so I
have added the module for the English
page you can see here okay and then uh I
have identified this particular link
which is cameras and then we are going
to click on it so this is all fine but
what if uh then we need to test it in
the French language right so if we
change this page to French then uh this
particular text is going to change now
it will work if there is uh unique
properties like ID uh which is unique
even if the language changes then you
can still work with that particular ID
but uh this particular link it has not
got any any particular ID as you can see
in the properties uh it is identified by
the inner text and the tag these are the
two properties with which it is
using so if you change the uh language
to French then the inner text is going
to change and then our test case is
going to fail right now one way is
obviously you can create multiple
modules for multiple languages but
that's not an efficient way of doing it
right so let's see how we can resolve
this particular problem so first of all
uh let's go ahead and create a test case
under this multilingual test case folder
okay so I'm going to say click
cameras so that's what our test case is
and then I'm going to drag this module
uh right here okay and then uh we are
going to click on this
right so this is all fine um if I
execute this and it's going to click on
the cameras
link but since I already changed the
language to French now this will not
work so let's see um first let it fail
and then um we'll see how we can fix
this particular problem
right okay so there are two problems
right now first of all to is not able to
find that particular link but before
that um before going to the link the
title of the page has also changed so
currently uh the title which tosa is
trying to find was in English but right
now the title has changed to French
right and how you can see that uh you
can even go to inspect uh in Chrome and
then you can search for title okay so
this is the title which uh is currently
there for this particular page so you
need to fix two things one is the title
and one is the link itself okay
okay so let's see um how we can do this
so this can be resolved by using regular
expression in your module attributes
okay so the two things which we need to
change is uh the title of this
particular module okay so here you can
see it is in English so what we can do
is uh you we can use regular expression
where we can use the or condition okay
so we can put two titles okay so
whichever title is present on the page
it will use that and it will identify
the element and the same we can do for
the link control as well okay so we can
put uh two different text uh which can
be in different languages now this uh
you can replicate for multiple languages
not only two but any number of languages
which you want to support right so for
every control uh you need to use the
regular expression where you need to
verify that particular control in
multiple languages
so uh let's do this okay um I am going
to first of all cut this and this will
basically start with an expression
called regx okay because we are going to
write a regular expression so you need
to write a regx which is the expression
starting with curly brace and then we'll
put a square bracket and then inside
this we are going to write our uh
multiple text in different languages
okay so we are going to start off uh
with the English language and I'm going
to reduce uh this text okay I'm going to
cut it and then I'm going to put a star
which means uh any character after this
text will be recognized okay no matter
what it is but the cameras from Nikon
will remain constant
okay then we need to put the or sign
which is this particular uh State State
Bar and after this you can put the text
which you want to identify in French
okay and that I have already shown you
so using this title we can find out this
so I'm going to use the initial part of
the text which is this okay and then
come back here and then we are going to
put it here again we are going to use
the star so that the remaining text can
be uh used as regular expression then we
are going to uh do double quote and then
close the square
bracket and then close the uh curly
braces okay so that will identify the
title now coming to the cameras link
right so we need to uh change the inner
text we need to use regular expression
here so the first text is in English and
then we need to put uh or condition and
then put it in French okay so the same
case like we did for title um again I
will take it out and I will start with
Rex okay and then square brackets double
quotes then put it across then the or
condition and then uh we need to
write this particular inner text in
French okay so this is the inner text as
you can see so I'm going to write this
uh particular text which is displayed
here so it will be
April then
photo okay and then I'll will also use
the star so that any if that particular
text changes then also it should work
okay so let me just verify so it's ail's
uh and then
photo okay and then uh we'll uh put
double codes uh and the square bracket
and and the curly brace okay so this is
uh the inner text using which this
control would be identified both for
English as well as French language now
uh coming back to our test case uh so
now it can be executed so let's see
whether it works for both the languages
okay so we'll start off with the French
language so let's run
this so as you can see it clicked on the
cameras link and then it came to this
particular page so both the title and
the link were
in French language even if we had
written two different uh text there
right but there was the Rex which helped
us to identify this control in this
particular language now let's change
back to English and let's see if this
still works okay so I'm going to the
homepage and now I'm going to run this
again
okay so let's go ahead and run this in
scratchbook again and this time as well
it should click on the cameras
link okay so it it clicked on the
cameras
link and this is how you can extend your
automation testing for multiple
languages which are supported by your
web application so this is known as the
multilingual testing and it is supported
by most of the test automation tools and
the same can be done uh in tosa as
well that's all for this particular
video If if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video